{"title":"ARTAUD","sources":{"MSUBJ":[{"source":{"id":"MSUBJ"},"mid":"artaud","starred":false,"content":"treason (can a subjectile betray?): not come when called [Artaud levels accusation of treason at God]","locations":{"raw":"pp. 154-57 ","list":[154,157],"high":157,"low":154}},{"source":{"id":"MSUBJ"},"mid":"artaud","starred":false,"content":"Artaud: soul is a fiend (<em>suppôt</em>), the else which is going to come back","locations":{"raw":"p. 162n ","list":[162],"high":162,"low":162}},{"source":{"id":"MSUBJ"},"mid":"artaud","starred":false,"content":"Artaud’s neologism <em>innée</em>, where nature collides w/ its contrary, “suffering of the pre-natal,” appears as monstrosity [Lacan’s extimacy?]","locations":{"raw":"p. 166 ","list":[166],"high":166,"low":166}},{"source":{"id":"MSUBJ"},"mid":"artaud","starred":false,"content":"“nature” conceals even the source of its interdiction > Artaud wants to tear apart veil of birth and reveal “naked nature”","locations":{"raw":"p. 166 ","repeat":true,"list":[166],"high":166,"low":166}}],"TC":[{"source":{"id":"TC"},"mid":"artaud","starred":false,"content":"Artaud: Plato must have experienced the streaming naked realization","locations":{"raw":"pp. 236-37 ","list":[236,237],"high":237,"low":236}},{"source":{"id":"TC"},"mid":"artaud","starred":false,"content":"Artaud rejects psychoanalytic theater for its secret interiority > theater of cruelty a theater of dreams, of calculated dreams, cruelty as consciousness, exposed lucidity","locations":{"raw":"p. 242 ","list":[242],"high":242,"low":242}},{"source":{"id":"TC"},"mid":"artaud","starred":false,"content":"Artaud: to consider dreams as substitute function, theater as second hand, is to diminish dreams & theater","locations":{"raw":"pp. 243 ","list":[243],"high":243,"low":243}},{"source":{"id":"TC"},"mid":"artaud","starred":false,"content":"Artaud wants to destroy all writing after reading it once; Artaud vs. Plato > both against writing: Artaud because it’s the erasure of body, Plato because it is body","locations":{"raw":"p. 247 ","list":[247],"high":247,"low":247}},{"source":{"id":"TC"},"mid":"artaud","starred":false,"content":"Artaud kept himself as close as possible to the limit, possibility & impossibility of pure theater","locations":{"raw":"p. 249 ","list":[249],"high":249,"low":249}}],"PS":[{"source":{"id":"PS"},"mid":"artaud","starred":false,"content":"for Blanchot, Artaud’s “unpower” is “essential to thought” > [Blanchot risks <em>neutralization</em> by making Artaud exemplary]","locations":{"raw":"p. 171 ","list":[171],"high":171,"low":171}},{"source":{"id":"PS"},"mid":"artaud","starred":false,"content":"[using Blanchot’s <em>pathetic error</em>, Derrida shows how Artaud's unique example, his history, will be erased on the way to truth, given to the doctors: a pre-Hegelian treatment]","locations":{"raw":"p. 171 ","repeat":true,"list":[171],"high":171,"low":171}},{"source":{"id":"PS"},"mid":"artaud","starred":false,"content":"Artaud howls under headings: existence, flesh, life, theater, cruelty > promising an art prior to madness & work","locations":{"raw":"p. 174 ","list":[174],"high":174,"low":174}},{"source":{"id":"PS"},"mid":"artaud","starred":false,"content":"Artaud’s resistance to clinical/critical exegeses: protest <em>itself</em> against exemplification <em>itself</em> > destroy history of dualist metaphysics, render doctor/critic helpless: art w/out works, language w/out trace","locations":{"raw":"p. 175 ","list":[175],"high":175,"low":175}},{"source":{"id":"PS"},"mid":"artaud","starred":false,"content":"Artaud’s metaphysics of flesh [MOP?] determines Being as life, its integrity must be restored > a thought governed by anguish of dispossession, my body stolen by the other, by death (as theft): my death is <em>represented</em>","locations":{"raw":"pp. 179-80 ","list":[179,180],"high":180,"low":179}},{"source":{"id":"PS"},"mid":"artaud","starred":false,"content":"Artaud wants absolute restoration of proper to eve prior to all dissociation","locations":{"raw":"p. 183 ","list":[183],"high":183,"low":183}},{"source":{"id":"PS"},"mid":"artaud","starred":false,"content":"Artaud wanted to destroy metaphor, the standing upright as metaphorical erection in written work","locations":{"raw":"p. 184 ","list":[184],"high":184,"low":184}},{"source":{"id":"PS"},"mid":"artaud","starred":false,"content":"Artaud uses Bergsonian-like formulations/metaphors of energy","locations":{"raw":"p. 325n ","list":[325],"high":325,"low":325}},{"source":{"id":"PS"},"mid":"artaud","starred":false,"content":"acc. Artaud, membering is dismembering; structure always structure of expropriation; “every organ is a parasite” of the body, the body has no need of organs; Heart: “dirtiest means that any being could have invented to pump life inside me” > Artaud as fearful of articulated body as articulated language","locations":{"raw":"p. 186 ","list":[186],"high":186,"low":186}},{"source":{"id":"PS"},"mid":"artaud","starred":false,"content":"Artaud: “words entered like knives in lasting carnation”","locations":{"raw":"p. 187 ","list":[187],"high":187,"low":187}},{"source":{"id":"PS"},"mid":"artaud","starred":false,"content":"Artaud: give words the importance they have in dreams","locations":{"raw":"p. 188 ","list":[188],"high":188,"low":188}},{"source":{"id":"PS"},"mid":"artaud","starred":false,"content":"reclaim onomatopoeia (gesture dormant in classical speech), “no more masterpieces”","locations":{"raw":"p. 188 ","repeat":true,"list":[188],"high":188,"low":188}},{"source":{"id":"PS"},"mid":"artaud","starred":false,"content":"Artaud: “I am writing for illiterates” > not to erase letter but to subordinate it to incidence of illegibility","locations":{"raw":"p. 188 ","repeat":true,"list":[188],"high":188,"low":188}},{"source":{"id":"PS"},"mid":"artaud","starred":false,"content":"Artaud seeks a depth of illegibility","locations":{"raw":"p. 189 ","list":[189],"high":189,"low":189}},{"source":{"id":"PS"},"mid":"artaud","starred":false,"content":"Artaud wants to renounce: superstition of the text, dictatorship of the writer","locations":{"raw":"p. 191 ","list":[191],"high":191,"low":191}},{"source":{"id":"PS"},"mid":"artaud","starred":true,"content":"Artaud affirms cruel law of difference while also fulfilling “most profound and permanent ambition of Western metaphysics”","locations":{"raw":"p. 194 ","list":[194],"high":194,"low":194}}],"REST":[{"source":{"id":"REST"},"mid":"artaud","starred":false,"content":"Artaud (protests against ghosts): no ghosts in Van Gogh, no visions, the torrid truth, hieroglyphics > Derrida cautions: “you can only give them [the ghosts] back (<em>rendre</em>) if you think you have them, and you can only think you’re giving them if you haven’t got them”]","locations":{"raw":"pp. 379-81 ","list":[379,381],"high":381,"low":379}}],"BSi":[{"source":{"id":"BSi"},"mid":"artaud","starred":false,"content":"Deleuze accuses psychoanalysis (Freud) of dispossessing (brutalizing w/ machines of war) the Wolf Man (much like Artaud’s complaint about theft of his proper name)","locations":{"raw":"p. 144 ","list":[144],"high":144,"low":144}}],"OG":[{"source":{"id":"OG"},"mid":"artaud","starred":false,"content":"[Artaud-like fantasy in Rousseau?] breath (of God), neume, superhumanity, not on the way to humanity (like child), body w/out organs, w/out spacing, pure presence w/ <em>jouissance</em>, inarticulate enough for <em>jouissance de soi </em>to remain uncorrupted by alterity","locations":{"raw":"pp. 247-49 (351-53) ","list":[247,249],"high":249,"low":247}},{"source":{"id":"OG"},"mid":"artaud","starred":false,"content":"via Rousseau, heart as organ of pure presence is not an organ, not inscribed w/in system of differences","locations":{"raw":"pp. 249-50 (354) ","list":[249,250],"high":250,"low":249}}]},"entryCount":29}